Guide to the George W. Fox Collection of American Indian Ledger Drawings and Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1867-circa 1885; Series II; 0.63; (3 boxes)
  - Photographs by John Nicholas Choate related to the United States Indian School
    - Studio Portraits
      - Studio portrait of Wat-ye-eh, also known as Benjamin Thomas; Kowsh-te-ah, also known as John Menaul; and Ki-ot-se, also known as Mary Perry; in native dress as they arrived at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, from the Laguna Pueblo, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Studio portrait of Wat-ye-eh, also known as Benjamin Thomas; Kowsh-te-ah, also known as John Menaul; and Ki-ot-se, also known as Mary Perry; wearing school uniforms, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Studio portrait of Yellow Bear (1842-1887) holding a feather fan, with his daughter, Minnie Yellow Bear, Arapaho Indians, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 73)
        Ink inscription image number on verso: 63.
    - Exterior Portraits
      Arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual or first person listed in the portrait or by the subject, followed by portraits of large groups.
      - Exterior portrait of carpenter apprentices installing a roof on a barracks building at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 74)
        Letterpress label affixed to the verso of the print identifies the left to right: Amos High Wolf (from the Pine Ridge Agency), Joe Gunn-Ponca, Samuel Wetzel (instructor), Phillip Good Voice (from the Rosebud Agency), Elwood Orlaw-Iowa, Charles Ka-Le-Ga, Matches-Cheyenne, E. B. Straight (carpenter), Oscar Bull Bear-Cheyenne, Ralph Iron Eagle Feathers (from the Rosebud Agency)
      - Exterior portrait of instructors and American Indian student raking ground recently plowed by a team of two mules operated by an instructor, 1880 April 20 (Box 4, Folder 75)
        Letterpress label affixed to the verso of the print identifies the view.
      - Exterior portrait of three Quaker women, identified as the Longstreth sisters from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, with Richard Henry Pratt and Spotted Tail (1823/1833-1881), also known as Sinte Gleska, Sinte-galeshka, Cin-te-gi-le-ska, or Tshin-Tah-Ge-Las-Kah, a Teton Indian, on the steps of a wooden bandstand at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 76)
        Photographic print has water damage.
      - Exterior view of a large group of Dakota Indian girls in front of a barracks building upon their arrival at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1879 October 5 (Box 4, Folder 77)
        Ink inscription image number on verso: 3.
        Letterpress label affixed to verso of the print: "Sioux girls as they arrived at the Indian Training School, Oct. 5th 1879"
      - Exterior view of a large group of American Indian girls from ten different tribes near a wooden bandstand and building in the distance at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1880 April 20 (Box 4, Folder 78)
        An erroneous letterpress label affixed to verso of the print: "Sioux girls as they arrived at the Indian Training School, Oct. 5th 1879."
      - Exterior view of Dakota Indian boys in front of a barracks building upon their arrival at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania; images includes Richard Henry Pratt, 1879 October 5 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Exterior view of a large group of American Indian boys from sixteen tribes at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1880 April 20 (Box 4, Folder 80)
        Ink inscription image number on verso: 2.
        An erroneous letterpress label affixed to verso of the print: "Indian girls (from 10 different tribes) at Carlisle Training School, April 20th 1880," and "Sioux girls as they arrived at the Indian Training School, Oct. 5th 1879."
        Ink inscription on verso of the print: "Indian boys from 16 tribes at Carlisle Indian Training School, April 20 '80. The ranks on the ground and lower porch show the same Sioux boys who appear in photo no. 1."
      - Exterior portrait of a large group of Dakota Indian chiefs from various Indian agencies, including Fort Berthold, Standing Rock, Cheyenne, Crow Creek, Lower Brule, Pine Ridge, Rosebud, Yankton, and Santee., 1879 (Box 4, Folder 81)
        Ink inscription on verso of the print: "Group of Sioux Chiefs, Carlisle, Pa. 1879."
        Image includes interpreters Louis Rubedo, John Bridgeman, Louis Premaux, Peter Beauchamp, and John Smith.
      - Exterior portrait of a large group of Crow Indians and Bannock Indians from the Crow Agency, Montana, and Shoshone Indians from the Lemhi Agency, Idaho, as well as Richard Henry Pratt and other European American men, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 82)
        Ink inscription image number on verso: 6.
    - Exterior Views
      - Exterior view of girls' quarters at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Exterior view of girls' quarters and bandstand at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Exterior view of boys' quarters at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Exterior view the principal's residence and laundress quarters at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, circa 1880 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Exterior view of a school building at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Interior view of the dining room at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, circa 1880 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Copy Photographs
      - Copy photograph of a slate board that belonged to Luther Otakte, a student at the United States Indian School in Carlisle, Pennsylvania; the board includes arithmetic exercises and a drawing of a man shooting a bird out of a tree with bow and arrow, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Copy photograph of a drawing, by George Catlin about 1832, of O-ke-hee-de, the owl or evil spirit, with body paint and buffalo hair breech cloth, dancing during O-kee-pa ceremony, circa 1880 (Box 4, Folder 90)
        Ink inscription on verso: "The first Indian boy who reported to Capt. Pratt at Ft. Berthold, Dakota, Sept. 19 '78, for education at Hampton, was called out of the medicine lodge and was painted and decorated as seen in this picture."
  - Photographs of the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway, Texas
    Organized under two headings: Photographs by Peter Fassold, and a Photograph by Samuel Burnett Hill
    The Buffalo Bayou, Brazos and Colorado became the first railroad operating in Texas after its charter in February 1850. In July 1870, it changed its name to the Galveston, Harrisburg and San Antonio Railway Company.
    Images of sites along the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway in Texas.
    - Photographs by Peter Fassold
      Peter Fassold (born circa 1843) was a watchmaker and jeweler, as well as an itinerant photographer known for his landscape views in the United States and Latin America.
      - Water tower and stairway on a canyon wall, Texas, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - Bridge of the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway, Texas, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - Bridge is distance of the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway, Texas, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - Depot on the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway, Texas, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway along a rock outcropping with a man posed standing, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway along a rock wall with an overhanging cliff, circa 1883 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Photograph by Samuel Burnett Hill
      Samuel Burnett Hill (1840-1917) was a photographer in Austin Texas, 1878-1912.
      - Railroad bridge over the Pecos River, probably the Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway, circa 1885 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Photographs of Texas and California
    Charles Turner Collier (born 1853) was a photographer in Riverside and Los Angeles, California.
    August R. Mignon (1844-1915) was a photographer in Fort Worth, Texas.
    - Collier, Charles Turner, Orange grove in California, circa 1885 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Mignon, August R., Large group of American Indians, probably at a pow-wow in the vicinity of Fort Worth, Texas, circa 1885 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Mignon, August R., View of the Washita River near Anadarko, Indian Territory, circa 1885 (Box 5, Folder 100)